<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Automate the Boring Stuff on Tutorials</title>
    <link>https://dragon-library.github.io/library/tutorials/docs/book/automate-the-boring-stuff/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Automate the Boring Stuff on Tutorials</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	<atom:link href="https://dragon-library.github.io/library/tutorials/docs/book/automate-the-boring-stuff/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>13. Working With Excel</title>
      <link>https://dragon-library.github.io/library/tutorials/docs/book/automate-the-boring-stuff/chapter-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dragon-library.github.io/library/tutorials/docs/book/automate-the-boring-stuff/chapter-13/</guid>
      <description>13 Working With Excel Spreadsheets Although we don’t often think of spreadsheets as programming tools, almost everyone uses them to organize information into two-dimensional data structures, perform calculations with formulas, and produce output as charts. In the next two chapters, we’ll integrate Python into two popular spreadsheet applications: Microsoft Excel and Google Sheets.
Excel is a popular and powerful spreadsheet application for Windows. The openpyxl module allows your Python programs to read and modify Excel spreadsheet files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>14 Working With Google Sheets</title>
      <link>https://dragon-library.github.io/library/tutorials/docs/book/automate-the-boring-stuff/14-google-sheets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dragon-library.github.io/library/tutorials/docs/book/automate-the-boring-stuff/14-google-sheets/</guid>
      <description>14 Working With Google Sheets Source : 
Google Sheets, the free, web-based spreadsheet application available to anyone with a Google account or Gmail address, has become a useful, feature-rich competitor to Excel. Google Sheets has its own API, but this API can be confusing to learn and use. This chapter covers the EZSheets third-party module, documented at https://ezsheets.readthedocs.io/. While not as full featured as the official Google Sheets API, EZSheets makes common spreadsheet tasks easy to perform.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>