<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Python on Tutorials</title>
    <link>https://dragon-library.github.io/library/tutorials/docs/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Python on Tutorials</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	<atom:link href="https://dragon-library.github.io/library/tutorials/docs/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Thailand</title>
      <link>https://dragon-library.github.io/library/tutorials/docs/python/pythonthailand/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dragon-library.github.io/library/tutorials/docs/python/pythonthailand/</guid>
      <description>Python Thailand Python Thailand - แหล่งเรียนรู้ภาษาไพธอนสำหรับคนไทย print(&amp;quot;Hello Thai Pythonista!&amp;quot;)  ยินดีต้อนรับเข้าสู่ Python Thailand เว็บไซต์ที่เปรียบเสมือนเป็นประตูบานแรกสำหรับคนที่ต้องการก้าวเข้ามาสู่จักรวาลของภาษาไพธอน เว็บไซต์นี้ได้รวบรวมแหล่งข้อมูลที่เกี่ยวข้องกับภาษาไพธอนที่ถูกเขียนขึ้นในภาษาไทย ไม่ว่าจะเป็นทั้งการสอนไพธอน เว็บบล็อกไพธอน รวมถึงวิดีโอที่เกี่ยวกับไพธอนต่าง ๆ ไพธอนนั้นมีประโยชน์มากมาย ไพธอนเปรียบเสมือนไม้กายสิทธิ์ที่สามารถช่วยให้เราสร้างสรรค์นวัตกรรมหรือสิ่งใหม่ ๆ ให้กับมวลมนุษยชาติได้
ด้วยเนื้อหาที่รวบรวมในเว็บไซต์นี้ คุณจะสามารถเขียนโปรแกรมด้วยภาษาไพธอนได้ เริ่มตั้งแต่การสร้างแอพพลิเคชันอย่างง่ายไปจนถึงโปรแกรมการคำนวณที่ซับซ้อน คุณจะเข้าใจหลักการสำคัญในการเขียนโปรแกรมทั้งในพื้นฐานทั้งหมดและในขั้นสูงที่เป็นการเขียนโปรแกรมแบบเชิงวัตถุ คุณจะได้รู้จักกับเครื่องมือที่ใช้ในการพัฒนาโปรแกรมหลากหลายรูปแบบ ซึ่งเนื้อหาเหล่านี้เป็นพื้นฐานที่สำคัญที่จะทำให้คุณสามารถนำไปพัฒนาทักษะการเขียนโปรแกรมภาษาไพธอน ของคุณในขั้นสูงต่อไป เช่น การพัฒนาเว็บไซต์ การสร้างเกม ฐานข้อมูล เน็ตเวิร์ค การจัดการกราฟฟิค
ภาษาไพธอน  ประวัติและต้นกำเนิด ตราสัญลักษณ์ของภาษาไพธอน ปรัชญาของไพธอน เกร็ดความรู้เกี่ยวกับไพธอน ทำไมต้องไพธอน ความสำเร็จของไพธอน   ดาวน์โหลดไพธอนและเครื่องมืออื่น ๆ  เริ่มต้นใช้งานไพธอน ระบบปฏิบัติการที่รองรับ ดาวน์โหลดไพธอน การติดตั้งไพธอน โปรแกรมแก้ไขข้อความสำหรับเขียนภาษาไพธอน ไลบรารี่และแพคเกจ   เนื้อหาไพธอน เลือกระดับความยากของเนื้อหา
 เริ่มต้น (Beginner) ปานกลาง (Intermediate) ขั้นสูง (Advanced)   โจทย์และการแก้ปัญหา  ระดับพื้นฐาน ระดับปานกลาง ระดับยาก โจทย์แข่งขัน คำถามสอบสัมภาษณ์งาน   หนังสือแนะนำ  Python ๑๐๑ คณะวิศวกรรมศาสตร์ จุฬา ฯ เชี่ยวชาญการเขียนโปรแกรมด้วยไพธอน ผศ.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awesome Python</title>
      <link>https://dragon-library.github.io/library/tutorials/docs/python/awesome/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dragon-library.github.io/library/tutorials/docs/python/awesome/</guid>
      <description>Awesome Python A curated list of awesome Python frameworks, libraries, software and resources.
Inspired by awesome-php.
 Awesome Python  Admin Panels Algorithms and Design Patterns Audio Authentication Build Tools Built-in Classes Enhancement Caching ChatOps Tools CMS Code Analysis Command-line Interface Development Command-line Tools Compatibility Computer Vision Concurrency and Parallelism Configuration Cryptography Data Analysis Data Validation Data Visualization Database Database Drivers Date and Time Debugging Tools Deep Learning DevOps Tools Distributed Computing Distribution Documentation Downloader E-commerce Editor Plugins and IDEs Email Environment Management Files Foreign Function Interface Forms Functional Programming Game Development Geolocation GUI Development Hardware HTML Manipulation HTTP Clients Image Processing Implementations Interactive Interpreter Internationalization Job Scheduler Logging Machine Learning Miscellaneous Natural Language Processing Network Virtualization Networking News Feed ORM Package Management Package Repositories Permissions Processes Queue Recommender Systems RESTful API Robotics RPC Servers Science Search Serialization Serverless Frameworks Specific Formats Processing Static Site Generator Tagging Template Engine Testing Text Processing Third-party APIs URL Manipulation Video Web Asset Management Web Content Extracting Web Crawling Web Frameworks WebSocket WSGI Servers  Services  Code Quality Continuous Integration  Resources  Podcasts Twitter Websites Weekly  Contributing  [](https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Cheat sheet</title>
      <link>https://dragon-library.github.io/library/tutorials/docs/python/cheat-sheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dragon-library.github.io/library/tutorials/docs/python/cheat-sheet/</guid>
      <description>Python Cheat sheet Useful tricks # Terminate a Python script early. quit() # For 1 statement on multiple lines, # use line continuation character (\). # Good for blog post. def __str__(self): return &amp;quot;Name={}, Title={}, Hourly rate={}.&amp;quot;\ .format( self.name, self.title, self.__hourly_rate )  String # Concatenation s1 = &#39;Open&#39; s2 = &#39;Writings.net&#39; print( s1+s2 ) # Output: OpenWritings.net # Object to string: Use str() function import datetime now_str = &amp;quot;Today is &amp;quot; + str(datetime.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>List for Tutorial</title>
      <link>https://dragon-library.github.io/library/tutorials/docs/python/list-python-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dragon-library.github.io/library/tutorials/docs/python/list-python-basics/</guid>
      <description>List Python Tutorial Python is one of the most popular programming languages. In the last few years, it has gained a lot of popularity due to the increasing interest in Data Science, Deep Learning, Machine Learning, and Artificial Intelligence.
Just have a look at the Google Trends chart for interest in Python programming language. It’s increasing continuously and it will keep on increasing over time.
Python Interest Over Time</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modules List</title>
      <link>https://dragon-library.github.io/library/tutorials/docs/python/modules-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dragon-library.github.io/library/tutorials/docs/python/modules-list/</guid>
      <description>Python Modules List Python os module
Python sys module
Python time
Python MySQL
Python CSV
Python multiprocessing
Python pickle
Python time sleep
Python queue
Python unittest
Python socket
Python SimpleHTTPServer
Python json
Python signal
Python random
Python System Command
Python Daemon Thread
Python Copy
Python threading module
Python struct
Python logging
Python subprocess
Python argparse
Python functools
Python itertools
Python getopt
Python ftp
Python tarfile
Python lxml
Python ConfigParser</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regular Expressions</title>
      <link>https://dragon-library.github.io/library/tutorials/docs/python/python-regular-expressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dragon-library.github.io/library/tutorials/docs/python/python-regular-expressions/</guid>
      <description>Tutorial: Python Regex (Regular Expressions) for Data Scientists Diving headlong into data sets is a part of the mission for anyone working in data science. Often, this means number-crunching, but what do we do when our data set is primarily text-based? We can use regular expressions. In this tutorial, we’re going to take a closer look at how to use regular expressions (regex) in Python.
Regular expressions (regex) are essentially text patterns that you can use to automate searching through and replacing elements within strings of text.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>