<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Flask on Tutorials</title>
    <link>https://dragon-library.github.io/library/tutorials/docs/python/flask/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Flask on Tutorials</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	<atom:link href="https://dragon-library.github.io/library/tutorials/docs/python/flask/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Primer on Jinja Templating</title>
      <link>https://dragon-library.github.io/library/tutorials/docs/python/flask/primer-jinja-templating/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dragon-library.github.io/library/tutorials/docs/python/flask/primer-jinja-templating/</guid>
      <description>Primer on Jinja Templating Flask comes packaged with the powerful Jinja templating language.
For those who have not been exposed to a templating language before, such languages essentially contain variables as well as some programming logic, which when evaluated (or rendered into HTML) are replaced with actual values.
The variables and/or logic are placed between tags or delimiters. For example, Jinja templates use {% ... %} for expressions or logic (like for loops), while {{ .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use a Flask Blueprint</title>
      <link>https://dragon-library.github.io/library/tutorials/docs/python/flask/flask-blueprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dragon-library.github.io/library/tutorials/docs/python/flask/flask-blueprint/</guid>
      <description>Use a Flask Blueprint to Architect Your Applications Flask is a very popular web application framework that leaves almost all design and architecture decisions up to the developer. In this tutorial, you’ll learn how a Flask Blueprint, or Blueprint for short, can help you structure your Flask application by grouping its functionality into reusable components.
In this tutorial, you’ll learn:
 What Flask Blueprints are and how they work How to create and use a Flask Blueprint to organize your code How to improve code reusability using your own or a third-party Flask Blueprint  This tutorial assumes that you have some experience using Flask and that you’ve built some applications before.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>